威尔 · 森特斯: 丹，说吧。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Dan, go ahead.
阿丹: 有两种，第一种是如果你有第二次处决的话
&gt;&gt; Dan: Kind of two, the first one
is if you had a secondary execution
上下文包装，能给我一个第二层的背包吗？
context wrapping, can you have
a back pack of the second level?
威尔 · 森特斯: 是的，绝对是的。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Yeah, absolutely yes.
所以，我会说，去实验，但它是一个链。
So, I would say that,
go experiment, but it is a chain.
这就是所谓的，我们马上就会知道它的名字，但是
This is what's called, well, we're gonna
learn the name of this in a moment, but
是的，当然，你可以去玩。
yeah, it is, absolutely,
you can go play with that, for sure.
但是，是的，这是一个链条，是的，第二个问题？
But yes, it is a chain,
yeah, second question?
你能有一个回调来访问数据吗？
&gt;&gt; Dan: Can you have a callback
that accesses the data?
威尔 · 森坦斯: 哇，那么你是说，我们可以在这里传递一个函数,
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Wow, so you're saying,
could we pass into here a function that,
- 你是不是...-是的,
is that what you're-
&gt;&gt; Dan: Yeah,
然后访问这些变量？
that would then access the variables?
威尔 · 森特斯: 是的，这就是所谓的功能装饰。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Yeah, so
this is what's called function decoration.
很多技巧都包含在，抱歉,
Many of the techniques enclosed in a,
sorry,
在函数式编程中使用这个原则,
in functional programming use this
principle, where you would pass,
我想做一个半成品的版本。
one knows a to detail, I want to do like a
half, sort of half-baked version of this.
去看函数式编程霍尔部分，我们这样做绝对完整,
Go watch the functional programming Hall
parts where we do this in absolute full,
但我们可以在这里加个函数。
but we can take a function in here.
我们可以在这里定义一个全新的功能，所以她得到了一个背包。
We can define a brand new function
in here, so she gets a backpack.
然后，该函数将可以访问参数函数
That function will then have
access to the argument function
传递到外层，当我们回来时，在它的背包里。
passed into outer,
when we return out in its backpack.
我的意思是，我们可以在背包里存储代码，然后运行这个功能。
I mean, we can store code in
the backpack and run the function.
这意味着返回输出函数将是，我们可以使它的行为变得漂亮
Meaning that that returned-out function
will be, we could make it behave pretty
类似于传入的函数，但是有一些变化。
similarly to the function that got
passed in, but with some changes.
它的表现很相似，因为它在幕后,
It's behaving similar,
because it's in the, behind the scenes,
用它的背包来运行这个功能。
gonna be running the function
from its backpack.
这是个半生不熟的答案。
That's a half-baked answer.
但是绝对的，你也可以在背包里存储代码。
But absolutely, you can literally
store code in the backpack as well.
这就是为什么可以携带、部分应用和
And that's what enables carrying,
partial application and
功能装饰技术。
function decoration techniques.
他们所有人都坐在这上面，但是坐在我们身上传递一个函数，这个函数的结尾是
All of them sit on this, but sit on us
passing a function in which ends up
在全新的退货功能的背包里。
in the brand new returned
out function's backpack.
这就是装饰的过程,
And that is the decoration process,
不同于其他语言的处理装饰。
different to other languages
handle decoration.
装饰就是你编辑一个函数或者看起来,
Decoration's where you edit a function or
appear to,
在现实中，你所做的，全新的功能，使用装饰,
in reality what you're doing, brand
new function that uses the decorated,
他背包里的变化功能。
the change function from his backpack.
这是什么东西，不要担心，如果你要去，这到底是什么意思？
That's something that, don't worry if
you're going what the hell does that mean?
但是，如果你想了解更多关于它去看函数式编程热点。
But if you want to learn more about it go
watch the functional programming hotpots.
可能是唯一一个。
Could be the, be the only person.
我相信它会非常受欢迎。
I'm sure it can be very popular.
肯定会爆炸的。
I'm sure it's gonna blow up.
好极了。
Excellent.
好的，谢谢你，丹。
All right, thank you, Dan.
问得好 Peter。
Great questions, Peter.
彼得: 非常类似，您称其中的计数器数据为 private，并且
&gt;&gt; Peter: Very similarly, you called
the counter data private within there, and
然后你可以在那里存储一个函数，这将是一个私有函数。
then you could store a function there, and
then that would be a private function.
威尔 · 森塔斯: 是的，二等兵这个词。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Yes, the term private.
我必须小心，因为所有这些术语都是一般术语
I gotta be careful on that because all
these terms are general terms that have
不同语言中有很多相互矛盾的定义，所以这是私人的吗？
many competing definitions in
different languages, so is it private?
好吧，只要我们能用它做某些事情，那么可能就不会。
Well, as long as we can do certain
things with it then probably not.
是不是我们不能突然随机覆盖
Is it private in the sense that we're not
able to suddenly randomly override to
全球记忆？
the global memory,?
当然。
Sure.
所以这些术语都要小心,
So just be careful with
any of these terms,
它们在不同的语言中都有点难以捉摸。
they're all a little bit elusive
across different languages.
是的，请讲。
Yeah, go ahead [INAUDIBLE].
发言人4: 网上有一个关于范围和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 4: There's a question
from online about scope and
基本上，范围在哪里发挥作用？
is basically where does
scope come into play?
威尔 · 森坦斯: 你马上就能看到了，绝对的，是的。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: You'll see it
in one second, absolutely, yeah.
是的，说吧，杰森。
Yeah, go ahead, Jason.
杰森: 错误传播，我们正在嵌套一些调用,
&gt;&gt; Jason: Error propagation,
we're nesting a bunch of calls,
我们正在进行一系列操作。
we're nesting a bunch of operations.
我仍然可以在这些变量上做一个访问错误,
I can still make an access
error on those variables,
我仍然可以请求一个不存在的数组中的 MSE。
I can still ask for
an MSE in an array that doesn't exist.
但是现在我们已经有了一系列的引用来传播我们的错误。
But now we've got a chain of references
to propagate our error through.
威尔 · 森坦斯: 是的，我的意思是这是一个有趣的挑战
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Yeah, I mean this is
this is one of the interesting challenges
当我们都使用传统的控制台日志时,
is that when we all using
traditional console logging,
我发现控制台日志我的新功能。
I find console log my new function.
它附加了一堆状态数据，这些数据在我的控制台上看不到。
It's got a bunch of state data attached to
it that I don't get to see on my console.
这很难调试。
That's gonna be pretty hard to debug.
当然，除非我们知道发生了什么。
Unless we know what's happening,
of course.
现在，亲切的铬开发工具给我们的能力
Now, kindly the chrome dev
tools do give us the ability
暂停我们的行刑。
to pause our execution at this moment.
如果我们这样做，我们就会看到右手边背包里的东西。
And if we do, we'll see the contents
of the backpack on the right-hand side.
他们给它起了个正式的名字，我马上就告诉你们。
They give it the official name,
which I'll tell you in a second.
有一件事我做了，没有人提出来，但我想提出来。
There's one thing I did, nobody raised,
but I do want to bring up.
说吧，马克。
Yeah, go ahead, Mark.
Mark: If in outer-Mark: 你创建了另一个变量-
&gt;&gt; Mark: If in outer-
&gt;&gt; Mark: You created another variable-
威尔 · 森塔斯: 问题是,
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: There's the question,
说吧，马克。
go ahead, Mark.
如果 incrementCounter 没有调用。
&gt;&gt; Mark: If incrementCounter doesn't call.
不引用，不引用。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: Doesn't reference,
doesn't reference.
马克: 不参考，他明白吗？
&gt;&gt; Mark: Doesn't reference,
does he get it?
威尔 · 森塔斯: 这是完美的，就像马克将要给出的问题一样。
&gt;&gt; Will Sentance: There it is perfect,
as in question Mark is about to give.
是的，问得好，马克。
Yes, fantastic question, Mark.
我们要弄清楚每个人都被马克问过这个问题。
We'll be clear everyone
got that question by Mark.
马克说等一下。
Mark said hold on.
但如果在我创造的这个本地记忆里,
But what if, in this local
memory I created, let's call it,
我不知道，马克的计数器，年份，还有这个。
I don't know, Mark's counter and
the year and this.
Mark 的计数器是7，返回的输出函数,
Mark's counter is seven,
the returned out function,
我可以编辑这个返回的函数吗？
can I edit this returned out function?
不，因此，马克的计数器放在背包里。
No, therefore, that,
Mark's counter goes in the backpack.
我可以直接在背包上买东西吗？
Can I get anything on a backpack directly?
不，我只能通过运行函数得到它。
No, I can only get it by
running the function.
所以我确切地知道，或者说 Java 确切地知道返回可能的结果的时刻
So I know exactly, or Java knows exactly
the moment of returning out what could
在那个背包里找不到。
ever be accessed in that backpack.
所以在现代版本中，JavaScript 的实现
And so in modern versions of,
the implementations of JavaScript in
我认为39英里 / 小时。
the chrome engine and
other engines as well, I think for 39 on.
优化---- 把什么放进背包。
JavaScript optimizes,
what is put into the backpack.
这个链接构成了整个本地内存，它只是指向这个链接到达的地方的一个链接。
The link is made the entire local memory,
and it's just a link to where that stops.
是的，这不是如果我们宣布马克的计数器里面的外部将是
Yeah, this isn't if we declare Mark's
counter inside of outer is gonna be
当我们完成外部运行时,
stored, it's just when we're
finished running outer,
通常都会被删除。
normally it will all be deleted.
相反，这个函数所引用的任何东西
Instead, anything that the function ever
makes reference to when it would get
最终运行，得到拉出与其背面的函数到我的新函数。
run eventually, gets pulled out with the
function on its back into my new function.
但如果 Mark 的计数器从未被引用从未被引用,
But if that thing, Mark's counter is
never referenced, never referred to,
从未被函数使用过，它会返回作业,
never used by the function and
it gets returned out jobs,
你可以直接查看这个函数，它有没有引用过？
you can literally look into this
function and go, does it ever reference?
没有，没有提到马克的柜台，只有柜台。
Nope, no reference made to Mark's counter,
only to counter.
所以在背包里是没有意义的，因为那就是我们所说的
And so there's no point in being in the
backpack cuz that would be what's called
内存泄漏。
a memory leak.
也就是说，使用计算机内存中的空间。
That is a say specifically,
use space in the computer's memory.
有了标签，就有了与标签一起使用的数据,
With a label,
you've got data used with a label,
我们再也不能做那个标签了。
where we can't ever act
as that label anymore.
所以数据是完全不可访问的,
And so
that data is completely inaccessible,
因为它实际上是在浪费计算机内存中的空间。
as it is literally just wasting
space in the computer's memory.
这就是内存泄漏。
That's what a memory leak is.
这里的情况就是这样。
And that would be the case here.
我们知道马克的计数器是7,
That would be stored,
we'd have Mark's counter is 7, and yet,
如果我们运行 myNewFunction，它就不会引用它，并且
if we ran myNewFunction,
it never makes reference to it, and
我们不能直接到达，所以这只是浪费空间。
we can't get to directly so
it's just waste of space.